RG 015:024, Office of Family Support
Connecticut State Library
Office of Family Support records
2001-2004
bulk 2001-2002
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut.Office of Family Support
3.75 cubic feet
The Office of Family Support was established by Governor Rowland after the September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks. It assisted families of the victims in locating financial, legal, and emotional assistance.
RG015_024
2007-037
Histortical Note
The Office of Family Support was established by Governor John G. Rowland shortly after the September 11, 2001 terrorist attacks. After the September 11th attacks occurred, Gov. Rowland personally contacted family members as the Connecticut victims became known. During each conversation, the Governor offered his assistance in any way needed. Many families took him up on his offer and began calling his office for help in locating financial, legal and emotional assistance. The Governor, realizing that his office staff would not be able to effectively handle the calls, set up a separate office to serve as a clearing house for information and as an advocate for the families. He assigned Office of Policy and Management Undersecretary Brian Mattiello the responsibility of assisting the families. Two staff members, DeAnna Paugas and Jim Sorensen were also brought in on loan from the Department of Children and Families and the Department of Mental Health and Addiction Services respectively, because of those department's areas of expertise. Mr. Sorensen was the official Director. The initial placement was within the Office of Emergency Management which had been collecting the names of the victims immediately after the event occurred. Later it was moved to the Office of Policy and Management. After Jim Sorensen retired and Brian Mattiello moved to the Department of Children and Families, the services became part of the Department of Children and Families for administrative purposes as Ms. Paugas also returned to her home agency.
The Office of Family Support was most active during the first year after the attacks. In the intervening years, requests for assistance dwindled to a few each year. The only real remaining activity is the coordination of the annual memorial service for the victims as part of "Remembrance Day" required by PA 02-126. In addition to assisting the families through the maze of assistance available to them, the office also oversaw the six-month and annual memorial services for the families. There was also a Connecticut Helps Oversight Council established which consisted of eighteen state agencies and volunteer organizations. They were in charge of coordinating all post September 11th health and human service activities ranging from those associated with victim's families to those population-based.
Scope and Content
Includes administrative files, support programs and services, case management, Office of Emergency Management, victim files, and memorials.
Arrangement
Series 1. Administrative Files, 2001-2004, .5 cubic foot
Includes Connecticut Helps Oversight Council, donor information, newsletters, and progress reports and budget.
Series 2. Support Programs and Services, 2001-2004, .5 cubic foot
Includes American Red Cross Emergency Family Gift Program, Cantor Fitzgerald, Family and Children's Agency, funds, insurance, Realtors Housing Relief Fund, Salvation Army, Trial Lawyers Care, Tuition Waiver Program, United Way Infoline 2-1-1, and Victim Compensation Fund.
Series 3. Case Management, 2001-2003, 1 cubic foot
Includes case management tools, contacts made by Governor Rowland, Connecticut resident and nonresident victim lists, family correspondences, family lists, and United Services Group.
Series 4. Office of Emergency Management, 2001-2002, .5 cubic foot
Contents from two notebooks from Office of Emergency Management.
Series 5. Victim Files, 2000-2002, 1 cubic foot
Arranged alphabetically.
Series 6. Memorials, 2001-2004, .75 cubic foot
Includes materials from six-month, one-year, two-year, and three year anniversaries, living memorial at Sherwood State Park, memorial board, quilt, photographs, and videotapes.
Related Material
RG005:039 Governor John G. Rowland records, Scheduling files and Legal Consul subject files.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Office of Family Support
Subjects:
Connecticut.Office of Family Support -- Records and correspondence; September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001 -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Agendas (administrative records); Correspondence; Invitations; Lists; Minutes; Newsletters; Photographs; Printed forms; Programs; Videotapes
Restrictions on Access
Office of Family Support records are closed to researchers. These records may contain confidential personal data restricted by law. Please contact State Archives staff for assistance.
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Series 1. Administrative Files, 2001-2004
  - Connecticut Helps Oversight Council (Box 1)
    - General, 2001-2003, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Meeting agendas and minutes, 2001-2003, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Members, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Operations manual, 2001, undated (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - Donors (Box 1)
    - Donor lists, 2002, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Special Olympic medals not delivered, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Thank you letters, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 2004, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, 2002, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Progress reports and budget, 2002, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series 2. Support Program and Services, 2001-2004
  - American Red Cross Emergency Family Gift Program (Box 2)
    - General, 2001-2004, undated (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Completed forms, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
    - Victim lists, 2001-2002, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Cantor Fitzgerald, 2001 September 20, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Family and Chidren's Agency, Inc. (FCA), 2001-2002, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Funds, 2001 December-2002 May, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Insurance, 2002 May-June, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Melanie Ilene Rieger Memorial Conference Against Violence, 2004 March-April (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Realtors Housing Relief Fund, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Salvation Army, 2002 January-April (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Trial Lawyers Care, 2001 December-2002 January, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Tuition waiver program (PA 02-126), 2002, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - United Way, Infoline/2-1-1, 2001, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Victim compensation fund, 2002 January (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Series 3. Case Management, 2001-2003
  - Case Management tools (Box 3)
    - Correspondence and notes, 2002-2003, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Documentation, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
  - Contact by Governor Rowland, 2001 September (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
  - Connecticut nonresident victim list, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Connecticut resident victim list, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
  - Database, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Database information forms, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Family correspondence (Box 3)
    - General, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 11-13)
    - Ford, James Henery Lee III, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Gerlic, Daniel, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Hanson, Lee and Eunice, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Higley, Vycki, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - LeJacq, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Family list (Box 4)
    - Lists, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - General, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Returned Correspondence, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Family notification, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - United Services Group, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Series 4. Office of Emergency Management, 2001-2002
  - Notebook 1, 2001-2002, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Notebook 2, 2001, undated (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
- Series 5. Victim Files, 2001-2002
  - Bennett, Bryan C., 2001-2002, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bittner, Jeffrey D., 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Blackwell, Christopher, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Boyle, Allen, 2002 September 25 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Braginsky, Alexander, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Brennan, Frank, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Brennan, Thomas, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Cappa, David R., 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Cherry, Stephen, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Cloud, Geoffrey, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Coleman, Scott and Keith, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Conners, Kevin, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Coppo, Joseph, 2001-2002, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Cummins, Brian T., 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Curioli, Paul, 2001-2002, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Eagleson, Bruce, 2001-2002, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Egan, Michael, 2001 December 19 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Ericson, Ulf, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Evans, Eric, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Faulkner, Wendy, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Fergus, Edward, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Fetchet, Bradley, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Fiorito, John, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Fisher, Bennett L., 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Ford, James Henry Lee III, 2001-2002, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Fry, Peter, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Gabrielle, Richard, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Gadiel, James, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Galvin, Thomas, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Garbo, Osseni, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Gay, Peter Allen, 2001 September 16 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Gelinas, Peter Gerard, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Gerlich, Robert, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Gillette, Evan, 2001-2002, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Gilligan, Ron, 2001-2002, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Glick, Steven Lawrence, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Gopu, Kiran, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Graff, Edwin III, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Greene, Donald, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Greenleaf, James Jr., 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Grehan, Pedro, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Halvorson, James D., 2001-2002, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Hanson, Peter, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Hargrave, Timothy John, 2002, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Heidenberger, Michele, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Heller, Joseph, 2001-2002, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Higley, Robert, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Hobin, James, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Hofmiller, Judith Florence, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Hughes, Paul, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Hunt, William, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Hynes, Thomas Edward, 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Iskyan, John, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Jacobs, Michael Grady, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Jardim, Mark, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Johnston, Billy, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Keane, Richard, 2001-2002 undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Kerwin, Glenn, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - King, Amy, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Klares, Richard, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - LaMantia, Stephen, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Lasko, Gary, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Lawrence, Robert, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Lenihan, Joseph A., 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Lozier, Gary, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Lyons, Michael, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Maloney, Edward "Teddy" Francis, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Mason, Ada, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - McCourt, Ruth, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - McEneaney, Eamon, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - McLaughlin, Robert Jr., 2001 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Meehan, William, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Mello, Christopher, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Metz, Raymond, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Miller, Joel, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Miller, Michael, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Monyak, Cheryl, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Morehouse, Lindsay, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Morris, Seth, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Murillo, Cesar, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Murphy, Christopher, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Nolan, Daniel, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Noonan, Robert, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - O"Brien, Scott J., 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Orloske, Margaret Q., 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Palazzo, Thomas, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Patrick, James, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Pelletier, Michael, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Piver, Josh, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Roger, Jean, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Rooney, Sean, 2001-2002, undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Rothberg, Michael, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Roux, James, 2001 September 19 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Sabbag, Jason, 2001-2002, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Sanders, Stacey, undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Schielke, Sean, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Schwartz, John, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Scott, Randolph, 2001-2002, undated (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Simon, Michael John, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Smith, Heather, 2001 November 13 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Snyder, Dianne, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Spagnoletti, Greg, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Spencer, George, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Statkevicus, Derek J., 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Staub, Craig William, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Sweeney, Madeline Amy, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Tarrou, Michael, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Theurkauf, Thomas Jr., 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Toyen, Amy E., 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Turley, John Jeffrey, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Ugolyn, Tyler, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Uman, Jonathan, 2001-2002, undated (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Vadas, Brad, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Varacchi, Frederick, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Waters, James Thomas Jr., 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Williams, Candace Lee, 2001-2002, undated (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Williamson, John, 2001-2002, undated (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Wilson, William, 2002, undated (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Winton, David H., 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Wodenshek, Christopher, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Wohlforth, Martin, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Works, John, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - York, Edward, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Zion, Charles, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Names of individuals, no info found, 2001 September 26 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Carstanjen, Christoffer, family not found, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Noack, Kathleen (McGarry), mistaken identity, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Gelagotis, Michael, not deceased, 2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 76)
- Series 6. Memorials, 2001-2004
  - Living Memorial, Sherwood Island State Park, Westport (Box 7)
    - General, 2002, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 2002-2003, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Victim name inscriptions, A-K, 2003 June 25 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Victm name inscriptions, L-Z, 2003 June 25 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Lower Manhattan Development Corporation (LMDC), 2002, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Memorial board and other memorials, 2001-2004, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - One-year anniversary (Box 7)
    - General, 2001-2002, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Family survey, 2002 May (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Invitations and programs, 2002 September 5, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Photographs (Box 7)
    - Lucy Williamson, "the quilt lady", undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Memorial board, 2002, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Sherwood Island, 2002, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Quilt, 2001-2003, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Quilt book, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Six-month anniversary (Box 7)
    - General, 2002, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 2002 January-March, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Invitations, 2002 March 10 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Invitation responses, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Programs, 2002 Febuary-March (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Two-year anniversary (Box 8)
    - Program, 2003 September 4 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Three-year anniversary, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Videotapes, 2002-2003 (Box 8)
    - Six-month anniversary, 2002 March 10 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Two-year anniversary, 2003 September 4 (Box 8, Folder 6)